《女子监狱》
第二季第七集
这里面不用放滤嘴吗
Yo, shouldn't we be putting filters in these?
滤嘴  我们在哪儿  乡村俱乐部吗
Filters? Where we at, the country club?
我们怎么不派发
Ooh, why don't we give 'em out
烟斗和皮草  就像库伊拉那样
with cigarette holders and fur coats like Cruella?
电影《101只斑点狗》中的坏女人
还有霍莉・戈莱特丽  她戴小皇冠
And Holly Golightly. She had a tiara.
电影《蒂凡尼的早餐》中的曼哈顿交际花
如果要放滤嘴  就得把香烟卷大些
Put filters in, you got to roll the cigarettes bigger to match.
那样会减少利润
Eats into our margins.
你说每支烟换一本食品券
You talkin' 'bout chargin' a book of stamps per,
你到手的利润已经挺丰厚了
you got pretty good margins already.
-一支烟几乎九美元  -胡说八道
- That's like nine bucks a smoke. - Oh, shit.
看来沃森
Looks like Watson
知道什么叫供求关系了
is gettin' introduced to our good friends supply and demand.
停手  警卫来了
Cheese it. Fuzz.
水槽里有块生肉  你能清理下吗
Would you clean a sink with a piece of raw meat?
你怕有细菌就不肯清理
No, you wouldn't, because of germs.
肮脏的海绵就像块臭肉
A filthy sponge is like a rectangle of smelly meat.
研究表明
Studies show
浴室水槽里的细菌比厕所还多
that bathroom sinks have more germs in it than a toilet.
-你得消毒  -消毒
- You gotta disinfect! - Disinfect.
你知道哪里的细菌比厕所还多吗
You know what else has more germs than a toilet?
你的嘴巴
Your mouth.
还有自动取款机的键盘和女人的包底
And also ATM keypads and the bottom of ladies' handbags.
我读到的
I read that.
我们在监狱里每天都能学到新东西呀
You know, we learn something new every day here in prison.
好吧  听好了  姑娘们
All right. Listen up, ladies.
如果让顾客选普通邮票和永久邮票
Now, if a customer's got regular stamps and forever stamps,
无论邮费怎么涨  该邮票永远可以用
她都会选永久邮票
she always take the forever stamps.
所以你就要囤货
You hold on to those,
等邮局涨价的时候
and when the post office jacks up the prices,
你就赚到了
you've made money.
你是说是你赚的钱  你可是要拿九成
You mean you made money. You taking like 90%, ain't you?
一把邮票弄出去  你的手下就能拿去变钱了
Sendin' those stamps outside, your boys turn 'em into bank.
我可是承担风险的那个人
I'm the one assuming the risk.
那我还冒着被关禁闭
Uh, what about my risk of sitting in seg
关到疯掉的危险呢
till I start talkin' to my hand?
你想要零风险  那就走
You want 0%, walk away.
姑娘们  这不仅仅是一桩生意
This is about more than just a business, ladies.
这是为你们自己争取权益
This is about making something of yourselves.
你给了她们想要的
You give those women something they want,
她们就会因此尊重你
they will respect you for it.
我干完了
Yeah. I'm done.
很好  交给美味
That's very good. Give 'em to Taystee.
可它们都是我做的
But they're mine.
我们谈过  苏珊娜  还记得吗
We had this talk, Suzanne. Remember?
我们每个人都有技能
We each have skills.
但你没有推销的技能
Salesmanship, not one of yours.
得让别人乐意才会买
Gotta make people feel more comfortable.
维  我们要把这些货放哪里
Yo, Vee, where we supposed to keep all of these?
我可不想关禁闭
'Cause a sister is not tryin' to go to SHU.
你有什么隐身斗篷之类的吗
You got some kind of invisibility cloak or somethin'?
你说对了
You could say that.
是我要求太高了吗
Am I asking too much here?
我有强加给你们什么办不到的事吗
Am I putting something on you people that you physically can't do,
像是跳探戈之类的
like dance the tango or something?
没有  我是要你们称职点
No. I'm asking for competence.
首先  让囚犯待在监狱里
For starters, keeping the prisoners in prison.
在我看来相当简单
Seems pretty simple to me.
别穿着沾了水果蛋糕的卡其裤
Not having a fruitcake in khakis
在大家面前走来走去
wander around in public,
要五个警卫押她出去
five officers hustling her out,
塞进车里  该死的就像小丑表演
putting her in a car like some kind of fucking clown show.
我在说你呢  本尼特
I'm talkin' to you, Bennett.
-是你把我一人丢在这儿的  -胡说
- You left me here alone. - That is false.
我当时也在这里
Yeah, I was here.
对  你拿着《鲈鱼大师》杂志到处晃
Yeah, you were patrolling a copy of Bassmaster Magazine.
我只是要很恭敬地说一句
I'm just saying, respectfully,
也许情人节并不是
that maybe Valentine's wasn't the best day
带着一堆人去酒吧看你表演的最佳时机
to take a bunch of people to see your gig at a bar.
又不是之前没人出去过
It's not like people haven't gotten out before.
送她去重刑监狱  刑期再多加几年
Take her to Max, stick a few years on her sentence.
这女人都坐了一辈子牢了
The woman's 100 years old.
还要给她加刑
We're gonna give her more time?
贝尔  我要你对那个囚犯实施全方位盯人
Bell, I want you all over that inmate like a fly on shit.
你跟着她  找出她逃走的路线
You follow her. You find out how she's running.
我们就好好问问她怎么样
How about we just ask her?
我已经问过了
I already did.
她告诉我她是从27街拿到手推车的
She told me she took the trolley from 27th Street.
等我们把这个漏洞堵上
I will deal with this officially
我会正式处理这件事
when we get the hole plugged up.
你要我整天盯着菲利斯・狄勒
You want me 'round the clock babysittin' Phyllis Diller?
如果你觉得浪费了你的才能和学识就告诉我
Let me know if that is a waste of your talents and education.
第二  记过配额指标
Second, shot quota.
我们得把这里好好整顿一番
We are gonna straighten things up around here.
我要你们每人每周至少记过五笔
I want each of you writing five shots a week minimum.
让这些姑娘们老实点
Keep these ladies on point.
-你要记过六笔  -这不公平
- And for you, it's six. - That's not fair.
我要你对她们狠点  我会盯着你完成的
I asked you to toughen up your game. I'll see you gettin' there.
这要烦死人了  卡普托
Gonna be such a bitch, Caputo.
光是文书工作就很烦
The paperwork alone.
去跟你妈说  也许她会给你写个便条
Tell it to your mom. Maybe she'll write you a fuckin' note.
滚出去
Get out.
犯人  你点名迟到了
Inmate. You're late for count.
-还有45秒  -你来不及走到那里
- I got 45 seconds still. - Not enough time to get there.
这算什么  《少数派报告》
What is this, The Minority Report?
抱歉  我要给你记上一笔
Sorry. I'm gonna write you a shot.
什么你  白人妞辛迪也迟到了啊
What you... White Cindy ain't gonna make it, either.
我看的不是白人妞辛迪
I ain't looking at White Cindy.
这绝对是种族歧视了吧
This is some racism right here!
不是  不过如果你不闭嘴就会算了
It's not. But it's about to be if you don't shut up.
这他妈的算什么意思
What the hell that even mean?
趴在地上  犯人
Get down on the ground, inmate.
你他妈在跟我开玩笑
Fucking kidding me?
我刚才说什么了
What'd I just say?
好吧  动作快点  公民们
All right, let's move it, people.
把你的鞋子脱了
And take your shoes off.
我都不知道我为什么还要废话
I don't even know why I even got to say it.
抱歉  我请你把汽水扔掉
Oh! Excuse me. I'm gonna need you to throw out that soda.
我还在喝呢
I'm still drinking it.
你还在喝
You still drinkin' it?
恐怖分子也是这么说的
That's what the terrorists say.
你是恐怖分子吗
You a terrorist?
扔掉
Throw it out!
拜托  快点  走  你  快点
Come on, people. Let's move it. Let's go. You, come on.
-好了  -小心点  女士
- Oh, yeah! - Watch it, lady.
让路
Move out the way!
机场紧急救援
Airport emergency.
到手
Got it!
棒呆
Oh, yeah!
中头奖了  宝贝
Ooh. Jackpot, baby. Ah. Mmm.
姑娘  我差不多都有11个了
Oh, girl. I got, like, 11 of those.
那个应该是防水的
That one's supposed to be waterproof.
我跟你说  姑娘
Let me tell you, girl,
你往它上面撒点狂暴果汁  会大事不妙
you get some Crunk Juice on that shit, not good.
红牛加轩尼诗混合饮料
看起来我们有麻烦了
Looks like we got a problem here.
我没问题的
I'm clean.
严格来说  是的
Technically, yes.
可是我不能让你肌肉紧绷上飞机
But I can't let you on the plane with these guns.
转身
Turn around.
能接到你的消息我很惊讶
I was surprised to get your note.
老实说  莱瑞并不太合作
To be honest, Larry wasn't all that cooperative.
莱瑞最近心情不太好
Well, Larry's in a weird place these days,
可以说是我的错
which is mostly my fault.
但我不能细说
But I can't get into that.
跟我无关  我只是很高兴他们让我进来
It's none of my business. I'm just glad they let me in.
有时候  低效率也挺好的
Sometimes, inefficiency works for you.
事情是这样的
Here's the thing.
我奶奶病得很重  我应该获得休假的
My grandmother is very sick, and I'm supposed to get furlough,
可是看起来好像没戏
but it doesn't seem to be happening.
我不知道跟我有什么关系
I'm not sure where I come in.
就是监狱制度不合理的典型案例
Just one example of how the prison system isn't working.
警卫渎职  滥用单独禁闭
Guard misconduct, overuse of solitary confinement.
外面的人应该知道里面是怎么回事
People on the outside should know what it's like.
帕波  监狱对待犯人本来就不公平
Piper, prison treats inmates unfairly.
如果周末不能放假回家探亲
If not getting a weekend off to visit the family
是最糟糕的事
is the worst thing...
我根本没说
I didn't even remotely say...
犯人挨饿  被强暴
Inmates are starving. They're getting raped.
并非没人报道
And it's not like no one's covering this.
只是没人在乎罢了
It's just that no one cares.
听着  我有过夜不能寐
Listen, do I lie awake
幻想凭一己之力
fantasizing about personally taking down an institution
靠几句铿锵有力的话
that is the single greatest stain
就推翻自奴隶制之后
on the American collective conscience
美国集体良知的最大污点吗
since slavery with the awesome power of my words?
当然
Sure.
可是在白天  我接受现实  这不可能的
But in the daytime, I've accepted that's not gonna happen.
我能做的  也许就是
What I can do, maybe,
查明利奇菲尔德消失的两百万去了哪里
is find $2 million that's gone off the books here at Litchfield.
你想要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
如果钱被挪用了  肯定是用到了某处
If money's being appropriated, it has to be going somewhere.
我猜钱都支付到一个
I'm guessing that there's some kind of shell corporation
空壳公司去了
it's being paid into.
电网的确有点问题
There is something going on with the electrical grid.
这里都归菲格罗亚管
Well, Figueroa's the official on the ground here,
也就是说要么她被愚弄了
which means that she's either being duped
要么她就是黑手
or she's in on the profits.
我要知道谁跟她订了协议
And I need to know who she's making contracts with
谁干活  谁供货
for labor, supplies,
她给谁开支票
who she's writing checks to.
好吧  好的  我会去他们为了
Okay, cool. I'll just look that up
方便我们调查我们感兴趣的事
in the handy inmate Internet they give us for
而提供的囚犯网络上查查的
when we get curious about stuff.
他们去年花了20万美元
They appropriated $200,000 last year
翻修了一个并不存在的健身房
to renovate a gym that doesn't exist.
我很想帮你  我会帮你的
Look, I would love to help you. I really would.
但是除了闯进菲格的办公室
But short of breaking into Fig's office
检查她的文件
and going through her files,
我不知道我该干什么
I'm not sure what I'm supposed to do.
我已经被关过两次禁闭了
I have been thrown in SHU twice already,
我很爱我奶奶  她可能就要死了
and I love my grandmother, and she could die.
我不会为了当个小间谍
I'm not gonna fuck things up for myself
美国喜剧电影
冒大风险给自己惹麻烦
by playing high-stakes Harriet the Spy.
好吧  如果你改变主意了就告诉我
Okay. Let me know if you change your mind.
对你奶奶的情况表示遗憾
I'm sorry about your grandmother.
你确定你就要做通常的发型
You sure you just want the usual?
所以才叫"通常"嘛
That's why it's called "the usual".
现在厨房都归你管
I mean, you're running the kitchen now.
你可以展示一下气场
You got room for a statement.
什么  我该把头发染成紫红色吗
What, should I dye my hair fuchsia?
是赤褐色  可惜不适合你
It's auburn. But not for you.
我觉得一个劲爆的莫西干头
I think a nice faux-hawk will give that
就能告诉别人"别惹我"
"Don't fuck with me" vibe, you know?
我主要靠脸来震慑别人
I mostly use my face for that.
喂  发胶
Hey, Aqua Net,
红妈让跟你说她开始种紫罗兰了
Red said to tell you she's got violets growing.
我难道应该在意这件事吗  为什么
And I should give a shit about this, why?
她说你会想知道的
She said you'd wanna know.
她想种什么就种什么  我不
She can grow whatever she wants. I don't give a...
紫罗兰
Violets.
你是对的  我会去看看的
Oh. You're right. I'll come check that out.
这里每天都让我越来越困惑
Every day in this place, I get more confused.
你带券了吗
Did you bring the stamps?
你为什么不先说说
Why don't you first tell me
是什么会让我超级兴奋
what I'm supposed to be so hair-on-fire excited about?
听着  多谢你的关心
Man, look, I appreciate your concern,
不过我卫生巾够用
but I'm actually well covered on the menstruation front.
就来一支
Just take one.
万福玛丽亚  你充满圣宠
Hail Mary, full of grace.
他妈的我要怎么点燃这个
Yeah, how the hell am I supposed to light this?
要钻木取火吗
What, I gotta rub two sticks together or something?
好好看着  利奇菲尔德牌打火机
Behold the Litchfield lighter.
我勒个去
Get the fuck out.
这可以算是我人生中排第三的好日子了
Man, it's like the third-best day of my entire life.
往下水道里喷
Man, blow into the drain!
然后评论家改了主意
What happened was the critic changed his mind
因为炖老鼠很美味
because the rat made stew, and it was delicious.
我明白
I understand that,
不过光靠炖老鼠可开不了餐馆
but that doesn't mean the rat can open a restaurant.
卫生法典还是要遵守的
The health code is still the health code.
你好像心死了
It's like you're dead inside.
我听说有什么紫罗兰
Um, I heard something about violets?
关门
Close the door.
你们居然会输掉冷战真是不可思议
It is a mystery to me how you people ever lost the Cold War.
等等
But wait.
用这个给我染发
This covers this.
你有被一个六英尺高的变性黑女人吻过吗
You ever been kissed by a 6-foot, black, transgender woman?
不用了  谢谢  不过我的小卖部需要帮忙
I'm good, thanks. But my commissary could use some love.
不是以货换服务吗
Whatever happened to goods for services?
我手头的现金有点吃紧
I'm running a little dry in the cash department.
你的货流渠道很稳定吧
You got a steady channel, I assume?
你想要什么就有什么
Whatever you want.
如果要求合理
Within reason.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
你在开玩笑吧
You cannot be serious.
弗洛雷斯
Flores!
那堆拉美人连像样的米饭和豆子都做不好
Bunch of Latinas can't make decent rice and beans.
到底是哪里出了问题
What's wrong with this picture?
我是吃中餐长大的
I grew up eating Chinese.
那时候我继父叫陈东  他有好多头皮屑
My stepdad from then was named Chen Dong. He had so much dandruff.
就是那个黑胡椒
It's that black pepper.
盒装的烂货  尝起来就像我外婆的骨灰
The shit that comes in boxes, it tastes like my abuela's ashes.
有次我叔叔烤了只被他碾死的穿山甲
One time my uncle cooked an armadillo he hit with his car.
味道还不错
It tastes okay
不过得放点辣椒酱才行
but you gotta put Cholula on it.
-现在有点忙  -抱歉  我该不该
- Kind of busy right now. - Sorry. Should I...
圣诞老人
Santa?
圣诞老人个鬼
Fuck Santa.
本尼特比圣诞老人帅气
Bennett's better looking
哪怕你不守规矩他也会给你礼物
and he shows up even if you've been naughty.
你那是什么
What'd you get?
这些玩意越来越小巧玲珑了
Oh, these things just keep getting smaller.
其实都是我的
That's actually mine.
你可以借几天  但我要拿回来的
You can borrow it for a few days, but I'm gonna need it back.
都是舰队狐狸的歌
Ugh. It's full of Fleet Foxes and shit.
-我的手机呢  -白人妞  现实点
- What about my phone? - Blanca, be real.
听着  这是我最后一次这么做了
Look, this is the last time that I can do this.
好吧  我不要手机  我要色情杂志
Okay, fuck the phone but I want porn.
老兄  弗洛雷斯真他妈是个天才
Oh, man. Flores is a fucking genius!
好吧  不过要高档点的
Okay, but good porn.
不要日本人那种变态的瞎扯淡
None of that weird Japanese bullshit.
我要只有男人的杂志
And I want a magazine with just guys in it.
怎么了  很性感啊
What? It's hot.
还有  我又不想看女人
And plus, I don't wanna be exploiting women and shit.
一点性欲都没有
It sucks out all the sexy.
我不会买同性恋色情杂志的
I'm not buying gay porn.
你是恐同人士吗
Are you homophobic or something?
各位  够了
Suficiente, everyone!
外面都是饿肚子的人  快点
We got hungry people out there. Vamos!
我大概会饿死
I may starve to death.
不用说  我是素食主义者
I'm a vegetarian, obviously.
我表示尊重  但是  此时此地
You know, and I respect that, but under the present circumstances,
我相当肯定  即使是
I'm pretty sure that even...
保罗・麦卡特尼也会对金枪鱼砂锅投降的
even Paul McCartney would be all up in a tuna casserole.
甲壳虫乐队乐手  素食主义者
看那个沙拉  就是冰冻豌豆和卷心莴苣
Look. That salad bar, it's just frozen peas and iceberg lettuce.
我要坚果  我要蔬菜
I need nuts. I need legumes.
-查普曼  -怎么
- Hey, Chapman? - Mmm-hmm?
你觉得我和冈萨雷斯
You think that me and Gonzales
能帮你一起弄监狱简报吗
could help you out with that newsletter thing?
-是的  再好不过了  -好吧
- Yeah, sure. That would be great. - Okay.
虽然可能有点奇怪
This might be weird,
但是你知道厨房的供货商吗
but do you know anything about the kitchen vendors?
比如杂货是哪个公司送的
Like which company delivers the groceries?
开卡车的人吗
Some guys in a truck.
-苏苏  -不要
- Soso? - No.
猪比狗要聪明
Pigs are smarter than dogs.
你吃蛋吗
Do you eat eggs?
那要看它是怎么被饲养的
Depends on how they were raised.
不吃呗
So, no.
你想拿我开玩笑就开
Okay, make fun of me if you want,
但是这个国家的农产品行业
but the agro-business complex in this country
真是完全疯了
is completely insane.
贱人  看看你周围
Bitch, look around you.
我们在监狱里
We in the prison-business complex.
如果奶牛能让我离开这里
A cow breaks me out of here,
那我就不再吃肉
I'll stop eating meat that day.
是真的吗
Is it true?
非洲的天主教牧师允许结婚
That the Catholic priests in Africa are allowed to get married
就因为对他们而言守贞太难
because chastity's just too hard for them?
我觉得对每个人而言都很难
I think it's hard for anyone.
对  但要是非洲男人
Yeah, but African men?
那又是另当别论了
That's a whole other story.
我相信你的话  失陪了
I'll take your word for it. Excuse me.
-姊妹  玉米面包  -哦
- Sister, the cornbread. - Oh.
就是我有低血糖  你记得吗
It's that darn blood-sugar thing. You remember.
我得给你记上一笔
I'm gonna have to write you a shot.
你要给修女记过
You'd give a shot to a nun?
不要恨我
Don't hate me.
我还从来没有被记过过
I've never gotten a shot before.
好日子到头了  真的
It's the end of days. I'm telling you.
行了
Okay.
-需要帮忙吗  -哦
- Can I help with this? - Oh.
谢谢  罗伯塔
Thank you, Roberta.
不客气
You're welcome.
昨晚我看见我丈夫了
I saw my husband last night.
听起来真不错
Well, that sounds lovely.
他现在玩贝斯了
He plays the bass now.
别忘了擦这些鞋子
Don't forget to shine those shoes.
我说过会给你理床  但不包括这些鞋子
Now, I said I'd clean your bunk. The shoes are not included.
我虽不是科学家什么的
I ain't saying I'm no scientist or nothing,
但鞋子也在这个床铺里  对吗
but the shoes in the bunk, correct?
光是待在这儿我可能就会被记过
Look, I'm gonna get a shot for even being in here.
如果我要再次面对纪律仲裁委员会
If I have to go in front of the disciplinary board one more time...
因果报应  你们白人是自食其果
You know, karma-wise, your people had this coming.
行了  这就是我能拿到的
Okay, yo. Here's what I got.
等等  我明确说过要草莓的
Oh, hold up. I specifically said strawberry.
我们没草莓的了
Well, we're out of strawberry right now.
那是我能拿到最好的了
That's the best I could do, all right?
我知道的是
All I know is...
我手里有高级货
I'm holding some premium shit here.
贱人  我不抽烟好吗
Bitch, I don't even smoke, okay?
我要用它收买阿蕾达  让她借我热水管
I need it to bribe Aleida to let me borrow her stinger
我好用热蜡除掉我的胡子
so I can wax my mustache.
幸亏你遇到我心情不错
Guess you caught me in a soft mood.
生日快乐  亲爱的
Happy birthday, baby.
-跟你姐姐说谢谢  -谢谢
- Say "thank you" to your sister. - Thank you!
有一阵子没见你了
It's been a while since we saw you.
你知道  工作真的很忙
You know, things been real busy at work,
不过我不会错过小个子的生日  绝不会
but I wouldn't go missing Shorty's birthday, no way!
我靠
Oh, shit!
-莫妮卡  -对不起
- Monica! - Sorry.
过来
Bring it here.
然后
Then... Unh.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
对一个九岁孩子而言有点过了
A little much for a 9-year-old.
你要是想说有点招摇  那你就说对了
Yeah, if you mean a little much swagger, you got that right!
我希望你能陪我过每个生日
I wish you were here for all my birthdays.
去年妈妈给我买了衣服
Last year, Mom got me clothes.
那是你需要的  宝贝
It's what you needed, baby.
我们去吃冰激凌怎么样  就我们俩
Hey, how about we go for some ice cream, you and me?
-好的  -过几小时就吃晚饭了
- Yes! - Dinner is in a few hours.
今天是个特殊的日子
It's a special occasion.
-你想要什么口味  -泡泡糖的
- What flavor you want? - Bubble gum!
我们仨一起去怎么样
How 'bout we all go together?
你担心什么
What you so nervous about?
你以为呢  我昨天才认识你吗
What you think, I met you yesterday?
我会看着她的  我保证
Look, I'm gonna look out for her. I promise.
她保证  妈妈
She promised, Mom.
去吧  但是要把iPad留这里
Go ahead. But leave that iPad here.
我不想你把它弄丢了或者被偷了
I don't want you losin' it or gettin' it stolen.
我们快走吧
Let's blow this joint!
-辛迪  -我知道
- Cindy. - I know.
查普曼  我就是想
Hey, Chapman, I was just wondering
你的简报委员会还缺不缺人
if maybe you got any room on your newsletter committee,
也许我也可以加入吗
that maybe I could join up?
我想想  目前就我和两个西班牙姑娘
Let me see. So far, it's me and two Spanish girls,
其中一个有点把我吓到了  所以  行
one of whom scares me a little bit, so, yeah.
我想我可以把你排进来
Yeah, I think I can squeeze you in.
真的太棒了
Oh, that's really good.
你有什么特别想写的吗
Is there anything in particular that you wanna write about?
我还没想那么远
Uh, I didn't really get that far.
我只是觉得让自己忙起来会比较好
I just thought it'd be good to keep busy, you know?
写写爱情小说怎么样
Well, what about romance?
像是长篇连载什么的
Like a serial type of thing?
狄更斯跟丹尼尔・斯蒂尔混合体
Dickens meets Danielle Steel.
我不想去碰爱情类的东西
I'm trying to stay away from the romance-type stuff,
-就是这一阵子  -哦
- just for a little while. - Oh.
没事  只是  也许可以写写其他的
Oh, yeah. No, it's fine. It's just, maybe something else.
很操蛋  对吧
It's fucked up, isn't it?
我们被困在这里
How we're stuck in here
可是外面的世界不断在变化
and the world outside just keeps turning?
是啊
Yeah.
写个美容专栏怎么样
What about a beauty column?
你总是那么漂亮
You always look so nice.
你知道  虽然你在监狱里
Well, you know, just 'cause you're in prison
但并不意味着你就能不管不顾了
don't mean you got to let it go.
我敢肯定你有些很好的美容心得
I bet that you have some great tips.
好吧  好吧  我可以写  我可以写
Okay. Okay. I can do it. I can do that.
谢谢你  查普曼
Thank you, Chapman.
-你有烟吗  -什么
- Hey, you got a fag? - A what?
烟  吸烟  烟头  抽烟
A fag. You know, a drag. A butt. A burn.
你是说香烟  你跑错地方了
Look, you talking about cigarettes, you're at the wrong house.
拜托
Come on, I'm not the one
又不是我开了黑人烟馆
who started a Negro-League Tobacco Shack, all right?
那是你的好朋友  维
That would be your pal Vee.
我只是想弄点好货
I merely seek to avail myself of a fine product.
她不是我朋友
She ain't my pal.
她朋友跟你朋友在一起
She's pals with your pals.
对  她就是利用你们给她卖命
Right, or she's using them to do her dirt
她只要数钱就行了
while she counts the cash.
她不会被发现跟违禁品有任何关系
You ain't gonna find her hands on no contraband.
你看着吧  如果有人因为运货被抓
You watch, somebody goes down for carrying,
她会在狱警面前装傻陪笑
she'll be shuffling and smiling in front of the COs like,
"上帝  这些姑娘干什么坏事了"
"Oh, Lord, what have these girls got up to?"
妈的
Fuck.
你知道高中生女同性恋的遭遇吗
Hey, you know that thing that happens to lesbians in high school?
我们和喜欢的直女
How we strike up a really intense best-friendship
建立起亲密的闺蜜关系的
with a straight girl who's really into it.
我们会劝自己能做朋友就很好  对吗
And we convince ourselves that friends is good, right?
直到她有了男朋友
Until she gets a boyfriend.
我们讨厌那个缺德鬼
We hate that poor asshole
讨厌到天怒人怨
with the white-hot heat of a thousand suns,
还说些"他配不上你"之类的话
a "He's not worthy of you," or whatever,
尽管他可能是个相当不错的人
when he's probably a decent-enough person, i mean, as guys go.
因为我们
Because what's really happening
其实是爱上了我们的朋友
is that we're in love with our friend.
为什么大家都觉得我爱上了她  我没有
Yo, why does everybody think I'm in love with her? 'Cause I'm not.
当然  当然  你要这么想就这么想吧
Sure. Sure. Let's go with that.
不过如果你的确是喜欢她
But in the event that you were having the feels for her?
你讨厌她的男朋友
Yeah, it turns out that by hating her boyfriend,
其实只会把她从你身边推开
you're just gonna drive her away.
你得接受这件事并让他喜欢你
I mean, you gotta suck it up and make him like you.
打打牌  把《教父》看十遍什么的
Take up poker. Watch The Godfather 10 times or whatever.
各位  警报解除  我们找到了
All clear, everybody. We found it.
不管怎样  这是你的人生
Anyway, it's your life.
你想怎么挥霍都行
I mean, spend it how you want, all right?
你的袋子呢  圣诞老人
Ay, where's your sack, Santa?
我做不到
Couldn't do it.
好吧  我再也不会这么做了
Okay, I'm not doing this anymore.
我看你是忘了敲诈是怎么回事了  老大
I think you forgot how blackmail works, papi.
我看你是忘了监狱是怎么回事了
I think you forgot how prison works.
这太过分了  好吗
This shit has gone too far, okay?
你知道还有谁很过分吗  你跟达娅娜
You know who else went too far? You with Dayanara.
好吧  这个怎么样
Fine. How about this?
你们都被记过了
You're all getting shots.
我什么都没干  混蛋
Yo, I didn't do nothing, asshole.
好吧  那你真可怜
Well, that sucks for you.
你他妈是在跟我开玩笑吧
You gotta be fucking kidding me, right?
我发誓我没在开玩笑
I promise you I'm not kidding.
本尼特
Hey, Bennett,
如果卡普托发现你强奸了囚犯会怎么样
what's gonna happen when Caputo finds out you raped an inmate?
-他不会发现的  -你确定
- He's not gonna find out. - You sure about that?
对  我很确定
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
因为你马上要被关禁闭了  拉莫斯
'Cause you're going to the SHU, Ramos.
-为什么  -我要再想想
- For what? - I'll figure it out later.
-你不会那么对我的  -你觉得我不会
- You ain't gonna do that to me. - You think I'm not?
走  动作快点
Let's go. Move it!
妈的
Shit!
你要跟她一起关禁闭
You wanna join her?
再见
Bye.
没想到这杂种还有这胆子
I didn't think that fucker had it in him.
我听说你想见我
I heard you wanted to see me?
查普曼  对的  请进
Uh, Chapman. Right. Come in.
卡普托先生  你有没有
Mr. Caputo, have you, um,
听到关于我休假申请的事
heard anything about my furlough request?
那不归我管  抱歉
It's not my department. Sorry.
不过我在考虑你的简报的事
But I've been thinking about this newsletter.
很棒
Awesome.
我想这会是一个很好的渠道
I've been thinking it could be a good way
让我们管理层
for us, the administration,
能够跟你们囚犯进行沟通
to communicate with the inmates.
来解释我们的立场
Explain our side of things.
你的立场是什么
Your side of what?
例如  现在实行的记过配额指标
For instance, this shot-quota thing we got going.
你们觉得我们刻薄
You ladies think we're being mean.
但我们只是做了本职工作
But we're just doing our job, you know?
事情变得失控  对大家都没好处
Things get out of hand, it's bad for everybody.
法西斯主义也是这么说的
That's kind of what fascists say.
我妈妈那边可能跟墨索里尼沾亲
I may be related to Mussolini on my mother's side.
开个玩笑
It's a joke.
也许你可以在简报里写点警卫的事
Maybe you could put something in the newsletter about the guards.
说明我们大家都是人
Show everybody we're human.
警卫  和我们一样
"Guards, they're just like us."
这就有点过了
I wouldn't go that far.
这个怎么样  "警卫
How about, "Guards...
他们也是人"
they're people, too"?
那么
So, uh...
告诉我
tell me...
你业余时间喜欢干什么
what do you like to do in your spare time?
你好
Hi.
-你是怎么回事啊  -好多事呢
- What is the matter with you? - So much.
你性致高昂地出现在我家
You show up at my house like fucking Squiggy with a hard-on.
你下次决定向丈夫最近才买了阿留申群岛狩猎矛
Maybe next time you decide to make some deranged declaration
而且乳导管堵塞的感情白痴
of love to an emotional zombie with a blocked milk duct
发表疯狂的爱的宣言的时候
and a husband who recently purchased an Aleutian hunting spear,
能先给我打个电话吗
you could consider calling first?
好吧  听着  波丽  我有点失控了
Okay, look, Polly, I'm spiraling out, okay? I am.
你知道有时候人设想生活应该是怎么样的
You know, you have this idea of what your life is supposed to...
不  我办不到  拉瑞
No, I can't do this, Larry!
好吧
Okay.
我认真的  这太傻逼了
I'm serious. It's just stupid.
我知道
I know.
没错
I mean, yes,
我们跟皮特和帕波约会前就是朋友
we were friends before we even started dating Pete and Piper.
我临产的时候  是你把我送到医院
And yes, you drove me to the hospital when I was in labor
办理了所有的书面材料  还细心照看我
and handled all the paperwork and the nurses.
当我丈夫消失不见
And yes, you were the only one there for me
去执行为期一个月的自我探索任务时
when my husband checked out of fatherhood
你是唯一在我身边帮我的人
so he could go on a month-long mission of self-exploration,
你很风趣  又恰到好处的一本正经
and you're funny, but also boring in all the right ways, and...
我到底在说什么  操我吧
What the hell am I saying? Just fuck me.
-我不知道这意味着什么  -闭嘴
- I don't know what this means. - Shut up.
好吧  听着  听着
Okay, listen, listen.
我好几个月没有性生活了
I haven't had sex in months,
所以我比较有可能
so there's a better-than-average chance that I could...
闭嘴  拉瑞
Just shut the fuck up, Larry.
你有说过什么乳导管堵塞吗
Did you say something about a blocked milk duct?
玩右边那个就好
Just stay to the right.
就像寄信一样
It's like sending a letter.
有个窗口  你输入问题答案就出来了
There's a box, you type in a question, and the answer comes up.
是谁在另一端查答案
Who's on the other end looking it up?
没人  都在电线里
Nobody. It's in the wires.
里面有世界上所有的信息
It's all the information in the world.
你说世界上所有的信息都藏在电线里
You're telling me all the information in the world is in wires?
但是人们还是很愚蠢  对吗
But people are still stupid, right?
红妈  我需要些火柴
Hey, Red. I could really use some matches.
火柴
Matches.
-对  -很好
- Yeah. - Good.
我刚还在想我们死在
I was just thinking our chances of dying
疯子纵火犯的燃烧弹下的几率还不够高呢
in some nut-job arsonist's fire bomb weren't high enough already.
我不会让其他任何人接触到它们的
I wouldn't let anyone else touch 'em.
拜托  我只是想抽支烟
Come on. I'm just trying to get my smoke on.
你有什么可抽呢
And what exactly are you smoking?
黑人有香烟
The black girls got cigs.
你需要打手
You need muscle,
塔斯利兹曾用斧头砍死过人
Taslitz killed a guy with an ax.
那时候她还没得关节炎
That was before the arthritis.
大波  虽然我很想帮你
Boo, much as I'd like to help you
让你下半辈子都关禁闭  可是我没空
spend the rest of your life in solitary, I'm busy.
你待会儿过来
Come back later
我会考虑给你点曲奇什么的
and I'll see about getting you some cookies or something.
真是的
Oh, man.
记一过  犯人
That's a shot, inmate.
为什么
For what?
损坏公共财物
Damaging government property.
胡说八道  你心里清楚得很
That is horse shit, and you know it.
你还想记一笔骂脏话吗
You want one for obscenity, too?
我觉得罗娜可以担任副主编
So, I'm thinking that Lorna can be assistant editor,
帮我们想想写点什么话题
help us come up with ideas of things to write about
还有谁来写
and people to write them.
所以你让两个白人妞来负责
So you got two white girls in charge?
该死的
Ah, shit.
我觉得应该让有能力的人担任  就这些
I just think it should be based on who earned it, is all.
我高中负责过年鉴  所以
I did yearbook in high school, so...
年鉴根本不是正式刊物
Yearbook isn't even a real class.
就是拍点照片  抽点大麻  大家都懂
You just take photographs and smoke weed. Everybody knows that.
不管怎样  我已经写了一个专栏
Anyway, I already wrote a column.
-我看看  -喂
- Let me see. - Hey.
这是我画的
Look, I drew this.
是关于监狱里的情况
It's about being in jail with,
用动物园里的动物作比
like, animals at the zoo.
为什么海象的心情这么差
Why is the walrus in such a bad mood?
那是海利先生
Oh. That's, um, Mr. Healy.
精彩绝伦
This is fantastic.
-你已经写错了  -谁说的
- You already made your first mistake. - Says who?
如果你能"少在乎一点"
If you "could care less,"
在口语里是couldn't care less的讹用
说明你还是在乎的
that means you still care.
懂吗
You know what I'm saying?
你当然可以少在乎一点
'Cause, like, it is possible for you to care less.
不对不对  我是说无论你有多在乎
No. No. I'm saying is however much you care,
我都不在乎
I could care less than you.
这句话不是这个意思
That's not what it means.
你应该说"我一点也不在乎"  懂吗
It should be, "I couldn't care less." See?
因为你的结论还是在乎的
Because you hit bottom with caring.
查普曼  跟她说说
Yo, Chapman, tell her.
严格来说  是的
I mean, technically, yes.
但我觉得就像"照字面意思"这个词一样
But I think this is one of those things like "literally",
口语中常表示真的  确实
最后总是越口语化的用法越被人接受
where the colloquial usage of the word eventually wins out.
语言是不断发展的
Languages evolve.
你为什么要那样
Why you gotta be like that?
关键是每个人都知道我要说什么
Look, the point is everybody knows what I'm trying to say.
你为什么非要犯浑呢
Why you gotta be a dick about it?
那叫语法  蠢货
It's called grammar, tonta.
我很高兴我总算找到你了  罗伯塔
I'm so glad I found you, Roberta.
-你还好吗  -不好  我被人跟踪了
- Are you okay? - No. I'm being followed.
是该死的爱尔兰人  我不能回大房间去
It's the damn Irish. I can't go back to the pen.
不准肢体接触  卡瓦诺
No touching, Cavanaugh.
太悲哀了
Oh, that is so sad.
你打算写什么
What are you gonna write about?
我在考虑  建议专栏
I was thinking, like, an advice column.
大家写下自己的问题
People write about their problems,
然后我会让她们振作起来
and then I tell them to get their shit together.
有一堆棒球类的呢  我最喜欢了
Mmm. Got a bunch of the baseball ones. My favorite.
有我在  你可以高枕无忧了
You know I got you covered.
-辛迪  -怎么
- Cindy. - Yo.
有什么要给我的吗
Got something for me?
事实是  没有
Oh. So, here's the thing. No.
也许你愿意来解释一下
Maybe you'd care to explain.
不是每个人都有券
Not everyone had stamps.
她们不知道你会找她们要券
They didn't know you was gonna be looking for 'em.
但不代表就不该给她们烟抽
Doesn't mean they shouldn't get a smoke.
其实  就是那个意思
Well, actually, that's exactly what it means.
这就叫生意
It's called commerce.
我让她们按老办法交易
I let 'em trade for it old school,
就像印第安人那样
like the red man.
贱人  相信我  你该给维的必须给
Bitch, trust me, you do not wanna short Vee.
她会化身金刚狼揍你
She will go Wolverine on your ass.
好吧  听着
All right, listen.
后面的烟我会多卖几块钱
I'll sell the next ones for a couple bucks extra,
好补差价
make up the difference.
如果你整包卖不好  你就别卖了
If you can't be trusted with the package, you can't be selling.
从现在起  你去做维护
From now on, you're on maintenance.
那是什么意思
What that supposed to mean?
就是你去干苏珊娜干的活
You do what Suzanne's been doing.
你给卖烟的人卷烟
You roll smokes for everyone to sell,
打包  收尾
package them, sweep up behind.
我不要干苦差事
I ain't doing no grunt work.
等你还清了债
When you've paid off your debt,
会给你机会卖烟的
you'll get another chance at sales.
去他妈的
Fuck that.
你顶替她
Take her place.
如果你想干的话
If you wanted to.
好的  我会考虑看看的
Yeah, I'll think about it.
我不怕你
I ain't scared of you.
说吧  莫妮  说吧
Say it, Moni! Say it, Mo...
-学校里怎么样  -还好
- Hey, so, how you doin' in school? - Okay.
-你喜欢其他孩子吗  -他们还行
- You like them other kids? - They're okay.
有些人取笑我  说我是呆子
Some of them make fun of me. Say I'm a nerd.
还说我没有手机
And I don't got a cell phone.
说我的名字照《老友记》里的控制狂取的
Say I must've got named after that tense girl on Friends.
净是些胡说八道
Man, that's some bullshit.
你的名字是照着
You was named after
《爱情与篮球》里的莫妮卡取的
Monica from Love & Basketball,
是桑娜・莱瑟扮演的
played by Miss Sanaa Lathan,
她才不是假正经  她跟丹泽尔搞上了呢
who, by the way, is so un-uptight she hooked it up with Denzel.
他都已经结婚了
And he married!
妈妈说那是谣言
Ma says that's a rumor.
不是谣言  而且妈妈很无聊
It ain't no rumor. And Ma is boring anyway.
靠  那是我伙计马丁吗
Shit. Yo! Is that my boy Martin?
我以为他还在监狱里呢
I thought his ass in jail.
他上个月出狱的
He got out last month.
看看这个
Watch this.
没门  我再打给你
No way. I'll hit you back.
你在这里干嘛  老兄
What you doing here, dawg?
我以为你在监狱里呢
I thought your ass was in jail.
拜托  我没那么蠢
Oh, please. I'm too slick for that shit.
你好
Hi.
我在匹兹堡找了一份政府工作
I got a government job out at Pittsburgh.
你疯了
This is crazy.
你一定要上楼来跟福滋打个招呼
Hey, you gotta come upstairs and say hey to Fozzie.
靠  福滋也在
Shit. Fozzie around, too?
他看到你的话肯定会尿裤子的
He's gonna wet himself when he sees you.
我要上楼十分钟
Look, I'm gonna go upstairs for, like, 10 minutes.
你就待在这里  好吗
You stay right here, all right?
等等
Hey, hey. Oh, hold up.
最多二十分钟  我保证
Twenty minutes, tops. I promise.
爱你
Love you.
孩子  来抱个  不  好好抱个
Yo! Son, give me some. No, bring that shit in.
来吧  伙计
Come on, man!
你最后拿那些电灯泡怎么办了
Hey, so what'd you end up doing with all them light bulbs?
你杀了我  啦啦啦
You slay me, dee, dee, dee.
旺达
Hey, Wanda.
我
I, um...
我想说对不起
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
有点太迟了
It's a little late for that.
是我搞砸了  事情进展得太快
I screwed up. Things were just moving so fast that...
我不小了  斯科特
I'm of an age, Scott.
你别占着茅坑不拉屎
You gotta shit or get off the pot.
再给我一次机会
Give me another chance.
我会搬进来的
I'll move in.
我会把榨汁机什么的都带过来
I'll bring the Vitamix and everything.
我想念你
I miss you.
过来  亲爱的
Come here, panda.
我也想念你
I missed you, too.
我研究了下女体解剖学
I've learned some things about the female anatomy
我想你会喜欢的
I think you might enjoy.
你对我朋友玛丽萨做了什么
What the fuck did you do to my girl Maritza?
她们敲诈我
They were blackmailing me.
她什么都不会说的
She wasn't gonna say nothing.
你觉得她会让我孩子他爸坐牢
You think she's trying to get my baby daddy locked up
让他无法抚养孩子吗
so he can't provide?
我不能冒这样的险
That's not a risk I can take.
那是我监狱里的妹妹
That is my sister in here.
我一点都不喜欢那个贱人  可她是我家人
I don't even like the bitch. But she's family.
我应该怎么做  告诉我
What am I supposed to do? Tell me.
难道要让这里的每个西班牙姑娘
Am I supposed to let every Spanish girl around here
都来欺负我
start pushing me around?
-上帝啊  -我是狱警
- Oh, good God. - I'm a CO.
你觉得要是他们看到
What do you think happens
我给犯人带小瓶装的酒会发生什么事
when they see me giving an inmate airplane bottles of Jaeger?
你不肯戴套的时候
Maybe you should've thought of it
怎么不想到这一点
when you didn't wanna wear a condom. Huh?
宝贝  我要出来了
"I'm gonna pull out, baby.
戴套子很难高潮
It takes so long to come with a rubber."
你明明知道  这不公平
That's not fair, and you know it.
滚蛋  我骂脏话了
Fuck you. I just used obscenity.
你要给我记过吗
You gonna write me a shot?
-达娅  我  -袭警  记我一笔呀
- Daya, I'm... - Assaulting an officer. Write me a shot.
怎么  没种的家伙  来呀
What, pussy? Come on. Huh?
我不会给你记过的
I'm not writing you a shot.
可是只要你想你就能记一笔  对吗
But you could if you wanted to, right?
因为你可以选择  你有这个权力
Because you have a choice. You have the power.
而我是个犯人
I'm an inmate.
我一无所有
I have nothing.
上帝啊  我讨厌老年人
Jesus, I hate the elderly.
女士们先生们  有请下一位州参议员
Ladies and gentlemen, your next state senator.
你想要讨论基础设施
You wanna talk infrastructure
或者洪水水位之类的  真遗憾
or flood levels or whatever, too bad.
每次都是相同的问题
It's the same goddamn question every time.
不  安迪・鲁尼
No, Andy Rooney,
我不会谈你那操蛋的医保制度
I am not gonna touch your fucking Medicare.
你说该说的  老头儿会投票的
Say what you got to say. The geezers vote.
你觉得我的头发看起来太闪了吗
Do you think my hair looks too shiny?
《都市邮报》报道说
Hey, so, City Post is reporting
罗利的PAC得到了  叫什么来着
Rowley's PAC just got a major donation from,
political action committee 政治行动委员会
高尔夫球场那家伙的大笔捐款
what's-his-face, the golf-course guy.
他们估计有150万美元
They put it at a million and a half.
我靠
Oh, fuck.
我敢打赌罗利肯定手舞足蹈得像只淫猴
I bet Rowley danced like a little monkey-whore for it, too,
那个贱人
that dick stain.
完了  我们死定了
That's it, then. We're fucked.
你可以走了  加文
You can take off, Gavin.
好的
Cool.
今天的演讲很棒  先生
Great speech today, sir.
非常有感染力
It was very powerful.
听着  我们不会放弃的
Listen, we're not giving up.
我们会想出解决的办法  我们还有选择
We'll figure this out. We've got options.
我很有压力  宝贝
I am stressed, babe.
有个记者在死死追问利奇菲尔德的事
I have this reporter buzzing around Litchfield
他就像该死的鲍勃・伍德沃德
like a Bob fucking Woodward.
《奥巴马的战争》作者
他什么都不会发现的  我保证
He's not gonna find anything. I promise.
听他意思就是  "当然  老兄
It's like, "Sure, buddy.
我们还是操心下给女囚建豪华浴室的事吧
Let's worry about funding luxury bathrooms for these ladies,
双淋浴喷头  各种各种
dual-action shower heads, the works.
别去解决什么判决法的问题
Don't bother fixing the sentencing laws,
让每个人都得到公平审判
guaranteeing a fair trial for everyone
和称职的律师
and a competent lawyer."
不  不  给她们浴球就行了"
"No, no. Let's give 'em loofahs."
我知道  我知道
Yeah, I know. I know.
人有时候真目光短浅
People can be so small.
我们会赢的  我保证
We're gonna win. I promise.
然后我们可以来解决真正重要的问题
And then we can get to work fixing what's really important.
我们是好人  我们会拉到资金的
We're the good guys. We'll find the money.
我们会在奥尔巴尼买栋房子
We'll get a house in Albany.
也许终于有个孩子
Maybe finally have a kid.
如果你想要孩子
If you wanna have a kid,
你就得跟我上床
you might actually have to have sex with me.
你知道  我
You know, I'm...
我总是精疲力尽  这件事让我心力交瘁
I'm exhausted all the time. This is so draining.
我知道  我很抱歉  我只是
I know. I'm sorry. I just...
我只是想感受到你想要我
I just wanna feel like you want me.
我不仅想要你  宝贝
I more than want you, babe.
我需要你
I need you.
你好  哥们
G'day, mate!
我开玩笑的  谁会那样说呢
I'm just kidding. Who even says that?
我得离家一会儿
I had to get out of the house for a bit.
波丽今天很让人厌烦
Polly has been a pill today.
我整个下午都在看孩子
I watched the baby all afternoon.
我跟她说出去兜兜风  随便她做什么
I told her to go spin or whatever it is that she does.
结果等她回来
And then when she gets back,
她的情绪比之前更古怪
she's in an even weirder mood than before.
女人啊  是不是
Bitches. Am I right?
你怎么了  哥们
So what's up with you, mate?
我不敢进去
I'm afraid to get in.
这水真冷
The water is so cold.
你总是能说服我
You always talk me into things.
好吧
All right.
见鬼去吧
The hell with it.
我来啦
Here I come!
从树上下去
Get out the tree!
我一般不碰树的
I don't mess with trees, generally.
你为什么要偷偷摸摸鬼鬼祟祟的
Why are you sneaking around all stealth and shit?
你他妈又不是粉红豹
You ain't the damn Pink Panther.
你真有趣  总是开开玩笑  插科打诨
You're funny, aren't you? Always joking, always clownin'.
这里还不能笑  那我们还能干嘛
We can't laugh in here, what else we got?
说得不错
That's a fair point.
问题是如果你只会开玩笑
Problem is when jokes are all you've got.
你就像故事里的蟋蟀
You're like the grasshopper in the story.
活在当下  今朝有酒今朝醉的人
Living for today, having a fine time.
没有责任  没有计划  没有抱负
No responsibilities, no plans, no ambition.
及时行乐  对吧
Carpe diem, right?
比你聪明的人早就说过了
Somebody even smarter than you said that.
当年这句话或许还有些道理
Yeah, well, that probably worked back then
那时的人四十岁前还可能出去
when folks were expected to check out before 40.
如果你不努力创造未来
Thing is, if you're not building a future,
那是因为你不相信未来的存在
that's because you don't believe there is a future.
是你自暴自弃
You've given up on yourself.
你就是个废物
You're a loser.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
我一直等你到半夜  都不知道你在哪里
I'm up waiting till midnight for you, no idea where you are.
一切都很好  我们只是晚回来了
Everything's cool. We got held up, is all.
这孩子才九岁  她衣服上居然有大麻味
The girl is nine years old. Her clothes reek of pot smoke.
她没抽  我又不是神经病
She ain't smoke none. I ain't no psycho.
让你带她出门是我的错
This is my fault for letting you take her.
你就是嫉妒她喜欢我比喜欢你多  承认吧
You just jealous 'cause she like me more than you. Admit it.
别给你自己脸上贴金
Don't you flatter yourself.
不管是谁
She would like anyone
难得出现  还送她礼物
who showed up here every once in a blue moon
她都会喜欢的  哪怕礼物来路不明
and gave her presents they didn't even come by honest.
该死的她是我女儿  我想做什么就做什么
I can do whatever I want with my own damn daughter!
你把她留在我这里的时候
You lost all right to call her your daughter
就再也没资格当她妈妈了
when you left her here with me!
你觉得我没资格  要不这样
You think I lost my right? How about this?
要不我们告诉她真相  看看她会选谁
Why don't we tell her the truth and see who she choose?
你不许那么做
Don't you dare do that to her.
她现在够大了
She old enough now.
你什么都不许跟她说
You ain't tellin' her nothin'
你就会自己走掉把她扔下
and then walk out and leave her.
你要告诉她  好啊  你去告诉她呀
You wanna tell her? Fine. You go on and tell her.
不过你要告诉她就得带她走
But then you got to take her.
也许我会这么做的
Well, maybe I will.
你能给这孩子提供什么样的照顾
And what kind of care are you gonna provide for that child?
你会每天去学校接她
You gonna pick her up every day from school,
带她去上钢琴课吗
take her to her piano class?
你能给她编辫子吗
You gonna braid her hair,
她生病的时候你能通宵陪她吗
sit up at nights when she's sick,
她吐的时候你能跪下来给她清理干净吗
clean up her vomit down on your hands and knees?
怎么  你觉得我办不到
What, you don't think I can do that shit?
那你带她走呀
You take her, then.
如果你觉得抚养她你能做得比我好
If you think you can do a better job of raising her than me,
请便
be my guest.
带她走  走呀
Take her. Go!
我怎么会知道呢
How should I know,
她什么都不告诉我
she doesn't tell me anything.
她整天画些奇怪的画
Spends all her time drawing her weird pictures.
你有花
You have a plant.
对  放温室里
Yeah. For the greenhouse.
这是我家灌木丛里开出的迷迭香
It's rosemary from my bush at home.
是一个全新的品种
Grows into a whole new plant.
不管怎样
Anyway,
很抱歉我昨天不得不采取严厉手段
sorry I had to crack the whip yesterday.
没关系  就是
No, it's... It was...
这工作看起来也许很简单  但并非如此
This job may look easy, but it isn't.
我有抱负  有一天我会成为典狱长的
I got ambition, you know? I could be warden one day.
记过配额指标能不能成功  谁知道呢
This whole shot-quota thing, who knows if it works?
管理层的人都喜欢有计划
The people upstairs, they like plans.
他们喜欢积极主动
They like initiative.
你得向他们展示你很有手段
You got to show 'em you're operating.
我明白
I understand.
有些人一点抱负也没有
Some people, they got no ambition at all.
他们就想得过且过  吃吃喝喝
They just wanna skate by, drink beer,
干得越少越好
do as little as possible.
比如卢斯奇
Luschek, for instance.
卢斯奇人很好
Luschek's nice.
当然  如果你喜欢那样的话
Sure. If you like that kind of thing.
我喜欢跟他聊天
I like talking to him.
跟懂你每天在做什么的人聊天
It's nice chatting with someone
是很开心的
who gets what you do all day, you know?
比如工作的事
Like, work stuff.
好吧
Okay.
我把这个拿出去
I'm gonna bring this outside.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
她还是你的女儿  阿蕾达
She's still your daughter, Aleida.
记住你怀孕时的样子
Remember how you were when you were pregnant.
我怀孕的时候  我跟我妈谈过
When I was pregnant, I talked to my mother.
你确定要用这种字体
Yo, are you sure about this font?
真的吗
Yo, yo, really?
本尼特不会提交玛丽萨的材料的
Look, Bennett ain't gonna file the paperwork for Maritza.
他只是想给她个教训
He was just trying to teach her a lesson.
她明天就会放出来的
She'll be out tomorrow.
我根本没提玛丽萨的事
I didn't say anything about Maritza.
可是你表现得很紧张
But you're acting like an uptight bitch.
只是因为你画漫画
Well, just because you're doing a comic
不代表你就要用漫画体
doesn't mean you have to use Comic Sans.
什么  小心眼
What... Hater.
我从没想到
I never would've thought
速溶咖啡可以用来画眼影
instant coffee could be used for eye shadow.
是啊  宝贝  它味道不好
Oh, yeah, hon. I mean, it tastes like ass,
所以不如用作化妆品
so it's actually better as a cosmetic.
谁会想到卡普托养了只乌龟
Who would have thought that Caputo had a turtle?
我还以为他喜欢养鸟呢
I mean, I had him pegged as a bird guy.
女主编  干得怎么样了
Madam Editor, how you doing?
我们其实都是副主编
We're actually all assistant editors here.
就像电视节目里
Oh, you mean like a TV show
所有名字都会在最前面滚动播放吗
with all those names rolling by up front?
他们不可能都那么重要
They can't all be that important.
我向你保证每个人都是不可或缺的
I assure you that everyone here is vital to the operation.
好吧
Oh, okay.
看看这个  海利先生
Check this out, Mr. Healy.
这是什么
What's this?
漫画
Comics.
很好的作品
Hey, good artwork.
海利先生
Hey, Mr. Healy,
不知道你有没有听说我准假申请的事
I was wondering if you've heard anything about my furlough.
你知道官僚作风  我会打电话问问的
Hey, bureaucracy, you know? I'll call around and check.
这是什么时候的事
Hey, when did this happen?
就是让他不要缠着我们
That's just to keep him off our backs, you know.
自负
Ego.
聪明  查普曼
Good thinking, Chapman.
好吧  继续干吧
All right, carry on.
那只海象真滑稽
That walrus is hilarious.
把我画的给我
Give me my shit.
拿那个的地方还有很多
There's more where that came from.
我知道
I know.
因为酸奶就是我做起来的
Because I invented the yogurt thing.
有点创意行吗  曼多萨
Have some originality, Mendoza, huh?
好吧  我没想到会是这样的
Okay, I didn't ask for any of this.
有等候名单  不过我会想办法的
There's a waiting list, but I'll see what I can do.
你想要什么  泥浆面膜
What do you want? A nice mud mask?
还是口香糖
Or is it gum?
由于某种原因突然间每个人都想要口香糖
Everyone suddenly seems to want gum for some reason.
她们是要用包装材料来做打火机
They're making lighters with the wrappers.
我一点都不喜欢这样
I don't like this one bit.
拜托  她卖她的  你卖你的
Please. She sells her thing, you sell yours.
井水不犯河水
It's no competition.
所以你站在她那边
So you're on her side?
不不  我不要黑市上的东西
No, no, no, no. I don't want no black-market shit.
我要香菜  你可以在花园种
I want cilantro. You can grow that in the garden.
成交
Deal.
-再种点辣椒  -别得寸进尺
- Some padron peppers? - Don't push it.
不过好吧
But fine.
那好
Fine then.
我要迟到了
I'm late for somethin'.
《狱中号角》
你总是把眼前的棋子都吃掉
You keep taking out all the targets in front of you,
可是你得想三步  苏珊娜
but you've got to think ahead, Suzanne.
如果你走那里
If you move there,
我会怎么走呢
what'll I do?
这就叫放长线钓大鱼
It's called the long game.
好吧
Okay.
好什么
Okay, what?
那差事我干
I'll take my medicine.
给她袋子
Give her the bag.
这是什么
What's this?
用过的卫生棉条
Used tampons.
不是卫生棉条
Not the tampons.
只是套管  垃圾桶里捡的
Just the tube-y parts. From the trash can.
你这是在整我吧
Now you just fuckin' with me.
卫生棉条在小卖部卖五美元
Tampons cost $5 at the commissary.
垃圾桶里用过的套管  免费
Used applicators out of the trash, they're free.
你以为第一批货是怎么来的
Where do you think the first batch came from?
总有人得做
Somebody had to do it.
真恶心
This is disgusting.
的确如此
Yes, it is.
这可好
Great.
我口渴
I'm thirsty.
喝我给你的水
Drink the water I gave you.
我不要水  我要果汁
I don't want water. I want juice.
你得等我们过了安检再说
Well, you're gonna have to wait till we get through security.
可我现在就口渴
But I'm thirsty now.
你有孩子吗
Do you have kids?
没有
Nope.
谢谢  我们走  宝贝
Thanks. Let's go, baby.
我不要去  我不要去  我不要去
I'm not going. I'm not going. I'm not going.
罗伯塔  别让他们带走我  罗伯塔
Roberta! Don't let them take me! Roberta!
罗伯塔  不要去  不要去
Roberta. Not going. Not going.
告诉我他们带走她是为了帮她
Please tell me that they're taking her to get help.
他们带她去公交站
They're taking her to the bus station.
她觉得林登・约翰逊是现任总统
She thinks that Lyndon Johnson is President.
第36任美国总统
她需要在专业机构接受全职护理
She needs full-time care in a dedicated facility.
放开我
Let go of me!
他们不会给她付钱的
They're not gonna pay for that.
她的家人呢
What about her family?
她有个女儿在斯德哥尔摩
She has a daughter in Stockholm.
可她们没联系
They don't speak.
那她就无家可归了
So she's out on the street?
这叫"以人道理由获释"
It's called "compassionate release".
罗伯塔
Roberta!